<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="st_dt2_warning_header">
        <text>Sentry</text>
    </string>
	<string id="st_dt2_warning">
        <text>Civilian, stop right there! Turn around or we will shoot to kill!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="st_dt2_fire">
        <text>Attention all stations: perimeter breach! You have my go-ahead for shoot to kill!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dt2_bandit_hello_1">
        <text>Hey where do you think you're going? This is our goddamn place, don't you see? Get the fuck out of here.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_hello_2">
        <text>...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_1_hello_1">
        <text>What's up with you freak, are you deaf or what? Get out of here before we break your face.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_1_hello_2">
        <text>...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_guard_1">
        <text>What are you staring at?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_guard_2">
        <text>Yo calm down, man, chill! Homie told me about a real deal for the right kind of homies like me, so I'd like to have a chit-chat with your boss about it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_guard_3">
        <text>I need to talk to person in charge.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_guard_4">
        <text>Yo chill bro, just let me through.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_guard_5">
        <text>Go on.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_guard_6">
        <text>Would you just look at him, get the fuck out of here and the further away you go the better.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_guard_7">
        <text>What? Who the fuck are you calling bro? Go fuck around somewhere else dude.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_guard_8">
        <text>...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_guard_9">
        <text>Whatcha need?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_guard_1_1">
        <text>Nuttin.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_guard_1_2">
        <text>Poker, let me pass.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_d5">
        <text>...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_start">
        <text>Welcome to our humble bar! Anything you need - just tell me, I have it all - drinks, food and more. The only thing missing here is women, but well, it is what it is for historical reasons...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_about_0">
        <text>I'm new to this place, can you tell me about the ins and outs?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_about_1">
        <text>OK then, listen carefully. We are now several kilometers away from The Chernobyl NPP Exclusion Zone. The Dytyatki 2 checkpoint is one of the entry points to the one and only Zone. So, if you ended up here, you've probably heard some rumours about profitability of this place. This is true, however the chance of you kicking the bucket is the same as in a flashpoint. This Zone is full of death-traps, like mutated animals or even humans - I've seen them with my own eyes - true criminals, hiding here from the law justice, the military and the military stalkers - they have their orders to shoot all illegals on sight. Not to mention all kinds of incomprehensible anomalous phenomena being observed all around the Zone, as well as radiation blowouts... Well, you know, the deeper into the Zone - the more terrifying this hell gets. \n
		But despite all of that there are several ways you can make a fortune. The main source is, of course, artifacts - these things of unknown origin, which appear close to anomalies all around the Zone. Believe it or not, but those things are capable of doing the impossible - they can even raise the dead from the graves. And you wouldn't be wrong if you think that these artifacts are worth a ton of money. \n
		This is the Zone in a nutshell, but these stories can go on forever - everyone who's been there has so many stories to tell that you could write several books.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_about_2_1">
        <text>Enough of bedtime stories, how do I get there?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_about_2_2">
        <text>Sounds even worse than atomic war... I bet you've "done your time" in this Zone?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_about_2_3">
        <text>Yo bro, quit selling me this bullcrap, do I look like a patsy? Keep yo' storytelling skills for eggheads, I've got better things to do than listening to yo' shit.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_about_3">
        <text>Dude, I don't want to dredge up things from the past. I lost my friends because of those criminals, so dealing with them is always more trouble than it's worth. The Zone is a horrifying and beautiful place at the same time. There are a lot of things in it that we will never understand, so hideous it can drive you absolutely insane, but at the same time magnificent and hypnotic. I myself could never make a fortune, otherwise you wouldn't be talking to me right now, but others could. I'm being drawn back to it, to be honest. Here, outside the Perimeter, endless nightmares from the past keep tormenting me, in my dreams I often hear the voice that's calling me back. But this is all irrelevant.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_about_4">
        <text>Gotcha, let by-gones be by-gones. Do you know how can I get there?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_about_5">
        <text>It's up to you. There are a couple of ways: I'd recommend you grease palm of someone from the local military men or talk it over with local guides. Warrant officer at the checkpoint will ask for a sizeable amount of lettuce, people say they even keep you waiting while they prepare everything off the books. The guides' services will cost you less, but in this case I wouldn't expect the military to give you a warm welcome on the other side of the Perimeter.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_about_6_1">
        <text>I see... But where can I find the guides?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_about_6_2">
        <text>I think I'd better get there "legally". Where can I find the warrant officer?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_about_7_1">
        <text>The guides are North-West from here, in a grey brick building that resembles a hangar, there are ruins West of that and the checkpoint itself North-East. The town is really small so you won't have any trouble finding them. When you get there, tell them I sent you, there is always somebody there hangin' around.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_about_7_2">
        <text>Then you just need to go north to the checkpoint. The warrant officer is most likely in the administrative building, as usual. And don't even think of running straight through the checkpoint, they will shoot you down like a dog - they have corresponding orders.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_about_8">
        <text>Alright, got it. Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_1">
        <text>Hey yo, I see you're a right type o' dude - go to our place, we'll talk it over. These dickheads won't really help you. Go outside and then straight ahead, tell the guys you want to see Foma.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_2_1">
        <text>Gotcha, will come over.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_2_2">
        <text>And who are you by the way?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_3">
        <text>I explain the local situation to clueless guys like you, even got my nickname "Situation" from that. I see you're new here, can tell you how things work here.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_4_1">
        <text>Nah, mate, I'm in a hurry right now. We'll have a chat and a cold one next time, cya.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_4_2">
        <text>Alright, yopta, hit me.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_5">
        <text>Step closer dude, c'mon, I really don't feel like shouting.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_p_1">
        <text>So here's the situation: this gutbucket belongs to the guy behind the counter you talked to just now. Here you will find all kinds of people, but mostly suckers. Further down the road there is the military checkpoint, absolute cunts, but you can make a deal with them in case you need to. There are mostly rookies, except some higher-ups, they can lock you up in a blink of an eye. Don't pick on suckers, they got their own crowd. Our gang doesn't do business with them, so all in all we don't interfere each other, they're all greenhorns, so you can't get anything decent from them. There are also swamp eggheads, sitting in their house and jerking off, he-he. We are Fominsky fraternity, our boss's name is Foma. We have a place opposite to this dump, you will find our boss there and talk it over. If you need to get into the Zone real quick, just tell him that. Capiche?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_p_2">
        <text>Sure thing! Well I'll kinda get going then.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_p_3">
        <text>Hey, wait, you think I've been going all out here for nothing? You gotta oil the wheels of yo' old fella. Go to that geezer and grab us a bottle o' cold one.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_p_4">
        <text>Now we're talking! Let's get started, fill it up... Well, to cut it short - to Fominsky gang, yopta!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_p_5">
        <text>Ohh fuck, it's bad without appies... [drink alcohol]</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_p_6">
        <text>Don't be a pussy, go for another one!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_p_7">
        <text>[drink alcohol]</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_p_8">
        <text>You awake, huh? Geez, go grab something to chase it down with.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_p_9">
        <text>Ohh fuck, my head is spinning and stomach aches. Be right back...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_ambassador_p_10">
        <text>Who're you?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_stalker_guide_1">
        <text>Why are you farting around here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_stalker_guide_2_1">
        <text>You two are the guides, right? I'm from Bear.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_stalker_guide_2_2">
        <text>What are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_stalker_guide_2_3">
        <text>Uhm... Just passing by.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_stalker_guide_3_1">
        <text>Quiet you! Wanna set us up? Listen man, It's the first time we are seeing you and Bear didn't tell us a jack squat about you. If you wanna talk, do us a favor.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_stalker_guide_3_2">
        <text>Now what do you need, comrade major? We are honest and law-abiding citizens. See you next time.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_stalker_guide_4">
        <text>What do you want?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_stalker_guide_5">
        <text>Yeah, well, it's nothing serious. Our "courier" left a package for us in a broken boat, if you follow the riverside from the bridge ruins you will find it in the bushes. The bridge itself is to the West. Long story short, we need you to grab this package and bring it to Bear. We aren't in the best situation right now to stick out like a sore thumb, you know. Any questions?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_stalker_guide_6">
        <text>Alright, I'll be right back.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_guide_1">
        <text>Bear, a parcel for you...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_guide_2">
        <text>Gotcha, hand it to me while nobody's watching.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_guide_3_1">
        <text>Ok, so I didn't get the joke, but it seems that I've been scouring the bushes for the sake of some rock. Here you have it. [give back only the artifact]</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_guide_3_2">
        <text>Here, a rock and a couple of banknotes. [give back everything]</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_guide_3_3">
        <text>I wanted to say that I would've had a parcel for you. But I've been stopped by a thug in those bushes and he took the rock, said it was their stash. Are you trying to set me up?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_guide_4_1">
        <text>Hell's blazes, money is all wet, need to hang it to let it dry. Alright, go back to the guides.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_guide_4_2">
        <text>Awesome, I'll ping our friends. You can go back to them.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_guide_4_3">
        <text>Of course not! You remember who it was? Alright, not a big deal, but I'll think over something to get even with those thugs...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_guide_5_1">
        <text>Alright, I'll get going then.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_guide_5_3">
        <text>Damned if I know, he was wearing a balaclava... I think it was one of those guys from the car workshop. He said I got it wrong and I've been fooled, like it was their stuff, and I'm just a patsy.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_guide_6">
        <text>Alright, that's what I thought. Listen, come back here later in the evening, we won't let this go unpunished.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_cs_ambassador_1">
        <text>Greetings, stalker-to-be. I represent free researchers, so to speak. If you are interested in exploration of the Zone, I can tell you a lot and even won't ask for anything in return!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_cs_ambassador_2_1">
        <text>I think I'd rather say goodbye.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_cs_ambassador_2_2">
        <text>You know, that is exactly why I came here...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_cs_ambassador_3">
        <text>Oh, say no more! I understood it all, so let's go over it step by step. In the Zone we call ourselves "Clear Sky" - kind of a faction. Our main purpose is to explore the Zone. But nonetheless, we don't work for the government or any third parties. Or at least we haven't been until recently, it's a rather long and tragic story connected to such phenomenon as "C-Consciousness"... In general, we are trying to make our scientific research useful for every living creature in the Zone. For instance, our technician Novikov has recently invented a new anomaly detector which is not only showing their location, but also highlights the location of the artifacts! We are also actively collaborating with official government ecologists, but for the military stalkers we are still illegal, yeah. If you're interested, on behalf of our leader I offer you cooperation.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_cs_ambassador_3_1">
        <text>I'm down for that, but first tell me more about the "C-Consciousness" story.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_cs_ambassador_3_2">
        <text>Sounds tempting, I agree.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_cs_ambassador_3_3">
        <text>I think I'll be better off on my own for now.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_cs_ambassador_4">
        <text>Erm... well, I was a rookie then and was on Cordon, running errands for some old cheapskate, and I heard others telling this story. I don't fully believe this all, but I'll tell you what I know. "C-Consciousness" is some super-secret project. The gist of it is that a group of scientists have united into a single overmind to control and research the
		Noosphere - information field of our planet. It seems like this caused the creation of the Zone. Our late leader Lebedev, professor Kalancha and Suslov were recruited and acted in the interests of this project. That means that group at that moment was unintentionally guarding the secret of the Zone. But one day stalker that went by the name Strelok infiltrated the centre of the Zone, and "Clear Sky" was putting all the efforts into stopping him and his accomplices. This resulted in the former leader's squad suffering severe casualties and losing most of their resources, and finally getting into an anomalous storm together with this Strelok somewhere in the vicinity of Chernobyl NPP. What happened next is unknown, the centre of the Zone was sealed shut, however Strelok found some miraculous way to return afterwards. I think the Swamp Doctor could give you more details. So this is how a bunch of ambitious adventurers chasing unclear goals got a huge number of people killed.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_cs_ambassador_4_1">
        <text>Well. So whats next?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_cs_ambassador_5">
        <text>Great, so you have to find our squad and they will help you with anything you need. From here directly to the West, last house at the end of the street.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_sleephouse_1">
        <text>Bear, where can I stay overnight?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_sleephouse_2">
        <text>I can offer you a place to lie down in the house, the one behind the bandits' garages. It's clearly more comfortable to spend the night having a roof over your head and there's also a potbelly stove, but keep in mind, you won't be the only one with the key, I have many customers. For 400 hryvnias you can use it till the moment you leave this place.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_sleephouse_3">
        <text>Deal. [give 400 hryvnias from non-cash account]</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_barman_sleephouse_4">
        <text>Nah, I don't agree with this deal.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_driver_1">
        <text>Wow dude, here I am standing and thinking how much longer are you gonna sleep inside.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_driver_2">
        <text>How long has it been since we arrived?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_driver_3">
        <text>Almost an hour standing here, the bus refuses to fire up anyway.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_driver_4_1">
        <text>Alright, I'll get going.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_driver_4_2">
        <text>Maybe I can help?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_driver_5">
        <text>Maybe you can. You think why am I standing here? This rust bucket refuses to start. I figure the plugs are dead, if you happen to find or trade some - I won't leave this favor unanswered. I know we have to have spares just for such cases, but the supply manager from the bus terminal, plague on him, this muzzle had fucked up an entire box of plugs. I'm Semionych, by the way, nice to meet you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_driver_6">
        <text>Okay, I'll see what I can do.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_item_barman_1">
        <text>Listen, one man needs help. Do you know where I can buy spark plugs here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_item_barman_2">
        <text>Well, there aren't any stores with spare parts, obviously, as well as the transport itself. Although there are some broken carcasses, but I really doubt there's anything left. I think the military should have some, go ask them.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_1">
        <text>Commander, I am here on a very important assignment.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_2_1">
        <text>I'm listening.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_2_2">
        <text>Oh! Come on in, I'll gladly hear out a good man.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_3_1">
        <text>Semionych, the driver, is stuck here. Spark plugs in the bus are dead. I think we need to help this man. He's got his wife and kids at home waiting for him! We just can't leave it like this. Maybe you happen to have some spares?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_3_2">
        <text>I need admittance authorization for entering the Chernobyl NPP Exclusion Zone. Is it possible to arrange?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_3_3">
        <text>I am an employee of RIChAZ, I've been sent on an assignment trip into the Zone to conduct research activities. You must escort me to my future command.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_3_4">
        <text>Ahem, I'm interested in various types of rifled firearms... So I wondered, maybe you have some decommissioned "surplus" pieces here lying somewhere or something like that...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_3_5">
        <text>Ah nevermind... I'll just keep on going.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_4_1">
        <text>Gotta help out a good man, you say, huh? Yeah, I've known Semionych long enough. Alright, listen, I'll see what can be done, but that will cost you a bottle of vodka. Come back later. And don't come back without the bottle.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_4_2">
        <text>Well, you do understand that we can't let everyone through? The entrance to Chernobyl Exclusion Zone is officially prohibited by the state. Crossing the perimeter and remaining inside is permitted only for a limited circle of people: military personnel doing their duties, employees of Research Institute of Chernobyl Anomalous Zone, military stalkers, journalists and security personnel. Do you belong to any of those categories?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_4_3">
        <text>Hmm, show me your ID first, please.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_4_4_1">
        <text>I don't understand what you're talking about, all decommissioned items are discarded and disposed of accordingly.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_4_4_2">
        <text>Maybe it's possible... I remember recently warrant officer was decommissioning Makarov pistols. I'll soon retire on pension, with length of service, and the shitty paycheck is almost nothing. I really wouldn't mind at least a 5k raise... Oh well... [shows the number of his non-cash account]</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_5_1">
        <text>Look, cold and tasty vodka...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_5_2_1">
        <text>Well I am a... Journalist aficionado, per se. I write articles and a bit of prose. I want to get into the Zone and tell the world about things that are going on here, and I heard that the most unbelievable things happen here.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_5_2_2">
        <text>Alright, I am a journalist-reporter, here is my ID. [show ID]</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_5_3">
        <text>Here, take a look.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_5_4_1">
        <text>Wait a sec, I just had somewhere... Ok check it now.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_5_4_2">
        <text>Ok, I'll run there right now and ask about the raise in payment for the military personnel. I will be right back.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_6_1">
        <text>Well, give it before someone will see... Take your candles.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_6_2_1">
        <text>Hmm... "Aficionados" have to make a list of papers... You know that we don't do it for free, according to standing order "About crossing of the perimeter of ChEZ", namely articles in the second paragraph, which by the way you can get familiarized with here in written form, we take a fee of 20,000 hryvnias for making a personal admittance authorization to enter the territory of ChEZ, managing your account in the database and more. This will take several hours. Are you ready to pay this sum in full with cash?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_6_2_2">
        <text>Alright, let's see... All is correct. I hope you fully understand how dangerous it is out there. Your ID is already a pass, I'll just enter it into our database. I will communicate this by radio to my subordinates and to the internal checkpoint so that they don't deter you. You can go, right behind that boom barrier, you will get to the inner checkpoint - our vanguard in defending the civil population from Zone's creatures. All the best!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_6_3">
        <text>Splendid... We can't escort you - that's the order from the government. I can't help, really, but you can talk with captain of inner checkpoint on Cordon, they have a helicopter. All the best!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_6_4">
        <text>Hmm... Oh yeah! Listen, come back in a bit, I'll have the stuff.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_7_2_1">
        <text>Sure, that's what I came here for. Here... I'll be back in a couple of hours.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_7_2_2">
        <text>I'm not ready yet, I need to think.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_driver_item_1">
        <text>Semionych, look what I found. Here, take it. [give him the spark plugs]</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_driver_item_2">
        <text>Oh man, you really saved my ass. Listen, I have a great backpack, got it recently. For tourists, the real stuff. It can handle any path you take. So take it and we're even, how about that?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_driver_item_3_1">
        <text>Sure. That's exactly what I needed, actually.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_driver_item_3_2">
        <text>Naw, Semionych, you better give me some cash. I'm broke currently.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_driver_item_4_1">
        <text>Nice! Good luck!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bus_driver_item_4_2">
        <text>Oh well, fine. I can't promise you gonna be rolling in the dough, of course. I don't have lots of cash in my pocket... Here, take these 400 hryvnias.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_weap_1">
        <text>I think I left some of my stuff here.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_kpp_commander_weap_2">
        <text>I thought you'd never return. Here... Everything is safe and sound, even with a little extra.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_trader_1">
        <text>Evening. Are you the enforcer here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_trader_2">
        <text>An hour well spent makes even stewed tea taste sweet. They call me Foma, I'm the boss here. Who are you?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_trader_3_1">
        <text>Me? Well, I... long story short - I got cops on my tail. I need to lie low and my homies helped me out, they say behind the Perimeter no one will be able to get me. Help me get there.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_trader_3_2">
        <text>Well I kinda got out of jail recently, I've got nothing at all, like zero. I want to make some money in the Zone, heard there are so many patsies - you can't even count them all.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_trader_3_3">
        <text>I heard there are no rules in that Zone. No cops, bureaucrats and the like. A real anarchy, yopta, like the actual heaven for me, I'm anarchist to the bone. I wanna get there.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_trader_4">
        <text>He-he, that's fucking serious! Alright, listen here: we help you - and you help us, deal? All fair and square.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_trader_5">
        <text>Sure, anytime, what do you need me to do?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_trader_6">
        <text>Alright, wait a sec... There's an old goat right over there in shithole across the street. He is playing all kinds of saint and holy Joe, meanwhile smuggling stuff right behind our backs. We don't do business with him, and don't rub elbows with him and all that shit. But taking our piece of the pie - I have no idea what made the old goat do that. That needs to be fixed, as you probably already understood. \n
		So here's the situation. In a hangar, South-West from checkpoint, there are two guides. Tell them you came from Bear and all that crap, we know that they need an errand boy and they work with the old goat and are dragging the stuff around for smuggling. When they let you know where their stash is, bring everything there is to us, don't worry about consequences, we will deal with them. Understood?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_trader_7">
        <text>Yup, ok, I'm getting down to business.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_blockpost_guard_1">
        <text>Long life! May I come in?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_blockpost_guard_2_1">
        <text>Long life. You know I'm not allowed to let each and everyone into the building. What business do you have here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_blockpost_guard_2_2">
        <text>Long life. Sure, you may pass.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_blockpost_guard_3_1">
        <text>I really need to talk to man in charge of this checkpoint, regarding the admittance authorization.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_blockpost_guard_3_2">
        <text>Did you drop this? It was lying right here on the porch... [give a bribe of 200 hryvnias]</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_blockpost_guard_3_3">
        <text>Oh well, fine. I'll get going then.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_blockpost_guard_4_1">
        <text>Well, alright, you may pass.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_blockpost_guard_4_2">
        <text>Oh really, I didn't even notice. Honest people are always welcome here, please come in.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_package_0">
        <text>I got news.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_package_1">
        <text>What is it?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_package_2_1">
        <text>All is hunky-dory, Bear has the package.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_package_2_2">
        <text>Ehh... So there was a hold-up...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_package_3_1">
        <text>Ah, yeah, we already know about that. You wanted to get into the Zone, right? We can guide you, favour for a favour, so to spaek, but you'll have make up - we'll just take 2000 to cover our expenses for supplies. Here, you can send the money to this account number...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_package_3_2">
        <text>Listen here, if things go South and our stuff doesn't end up in our hands, you will answer for it with your life. Alright?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_package_4_1_1">
        <text>Deal. [transfer 2000 hryvnias to non-cash account]</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_package_4_1_2">
        <text>Hell no, I'll better handle it by myself.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_package_4_2">
        <text>Understood.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_package_5">
        <text>Come back when it starts to get dark, around 7 PM.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_guide_1">
        <text>It's getting dark. Now we get rolling?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_guide_2">
        <text>Sure. But for starters here is a briefing for you. Firstly, you will be guided by my friend. Secondly, move as close to him as possible, don't lag behind. He will lead you to our creephole, you get on the other side and after that it's pretty much just the matter of how fast you get to the Cordon fence, there we also have a creephole. Whole distance from fence to fence is not observed by the military, you can say it's safe. But when you get into vicinity of the Cordon checkpoint - flank it left through the bushes, that means you need to move in North-West direction, alongside the fence. You will also find aperture there, that will be your direct way into the Zone. 
		\nBut here's the most important thing! The moment you move through the hole in the fence (third one already), you will find yourself at the minefield. It doesn't get updated very often, neither is it too thick, you can pass through. Just peel at the ground, you will see the pins where mines are placed. All in all, this is more a protection from mutants, not from humans. Go between those in the direction away from the fence. If you can't see shit - just sit in the bushes, wait until it gets light. Also I don't recommend using flashlight. Although these are our worthless military scum, they can notice you and then you gonna be screwed. Also one of my buddies told me that if you throw something into that mine (if you have anything to throw), and if you hear a barely audible click - it won't blow up. I didn't test this myself, neither would I take such a risk. That thing has effective radius so big that you almost can't hit it from a safe distance. All is clear?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_guide_3_1">
        <text>Yes, we can go now.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_guide_3_2">
        <text>Not really, could you repeat that please?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_guide_4_1">
        <text>Cool, then follow my buddy.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_guide_4_2">
        <text>We've got no time, move out. If anything - he will tell you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_guide_5">
        <text>Let's go then.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_fima_1">
        <text>Look, this is our creephole. After that you can run across fields and forests straight and you will get to Cordon, it's safe.  You will then find another creephole in the wire mesh. Go around the left side of checkpoint, and you will find an aperture. There's a minefield there, but the mines are marked, so they are easy to bypass. Well, you're on your own now.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_fima_2_1">
        <text>Wait, you won't lead me further?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_fima_2_2">
        <text>Alright, see you later.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_fima_3">
        <text>Dude, for 2000 it's as far as I go. For 5k extra I can lead you through the minefield, even up till our village. Deal?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_fima_4_1">
        <text>Fine, I get it, I get it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guiders_fima_4_2">
        <text>Deal.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_guide_send_warning">
        <text>Why are you stuck behind? Move here, quickly.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_take_1">
        <text>Foma, look what I found. Dough, although it's wet, and a round rock. Why the fuck are you collecting rocks?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_take_2">
        <text>It's an artifact you idiot. From the Zone. You can find such things in anomalies there, they cost a crapton of money, you understand? This junk will cost around 4k. We'll dry up the money and it's gonna be fine, just have to put them close to the fire. \n
		Okay, now down to business - scratch my back and I'll scratch yours. You wanted to get into the Zone? No shit, we'll organize that. We have our own creephole which leads into the tunnel in Darkscape. Ostap will lead you there. But first you need to understand - you won't be able to get back, the path leads down under the ground through a hole, so to get back to the surface you'll need a ladder. Long story short, he'll tell ya all the details, come back around 7 PM when it's getting dark.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_take_3_1">
        <text>Gotcha, I'll be back later. Maybe you have something else you want me to do?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_take_3_2">
        <text>Alright, see ya in the evening.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_take_4">
        <text>I've got something exactly for you. These suckers obviously have more than one stash. Keep an eye on those fancy pants that are chillin' in the hangar. Sooner or later you'll see them go somewhere, so if you're lucky enough - they'll lead you straight to their stash. Just don't let them notice you, cuz the business is screwed if they do. When you're in place - take everything there is and get back to me.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_take_5_1">
        <text>Hell naw, I'm fucking sick of running after those freaks.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_take_5_2">
        <text>Alrighty, I'll do it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_leader_0">
        <text>Good day...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_leader_1">
        <text>Hey man! You came here to talk or to do business?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_leader_2">
        <text>Good day to you, I've been told by Assistant in the bar there's a club of radiotechnology enthusiasts here...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_leader_3">
        <text>He-he, well, you can put it that way. Wanna join? I see it in your eyes that you wanna do it. We have to do one thing, and it's not quite legal, but it will probably help  filling the gaps in our knowledge about the Zone. After that we can talk about being a member of our faction, deal?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_leader_4_1">
        <text>Deal, tell me what needs to be done.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_leader_4_2">
        <text>No and no, I won't participate in such a thing.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_leader_5">
        <text>I'll tell you about it in short. Somewhere in the building at the checkpoint should be a file with documents, which are very interesting to us. We don't exactly know about its contents, but nevertheless. We know for a fact that these docs should've been delivered there just by this moment, and in the evening right after the changing of the guards they will send it further, so today is the last day. You'll have to get inside the checkpoint, carefully look around and take the files that look like they contain something very important. \n 
		You can try to bribe the sentry at the entrance, or think about some other ways to make it. Also all the sentries that are outside usually run inside when it starts to rain, so it will be much more difficult to steal the file and not get caught, keep that in mind. If you have the eyes staring at you everywhere, you can try to distract them, hell, even blow up something that's close.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_leader_6_1">
        <text>No and no, I won't participate in such a thing.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_leader_6_2">
        <text>Confirmed, will be back with the docs soon.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_leader_docs_1">
        <text>You have the papers? You can't go further without them.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_leader_docs_2_1">
        <text>Yes, I have them. Here, look...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_leader_docs_2_2">
        <text>Working on it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_leader_docs_3">
        <text>Great, give them to me quickly... Yes, looks like there's something valuable in them, I have to take a closer look. It's hard to determine their importance right now. \n
		Congratulations, you can consider yourself a member of "Clear Sky" faction! You have to get to our base in Swamps. I'm sure you can't wait to get into the Zone. And you're really lucky, because our guides are among the best out there in the Zone. Meet me here in the evening, around 19 hundred, when it's getting dark, and then we'll discuss the details.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_leader_docs_4">
        <text>Got it, see you later.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_robbery_1">
        <text>Hey what the fuck, are you out of your fucking mind?! It's our stash! Give me the stuff and get the fuck out of here while I haven't broken your spine.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_robbery_2">
        <text>What? This stash belongs to Bear and his guides, I came here to take their stuff.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_robbery_3">
        <text>What? Quit bullshitting me, dude! That sucker double-crossed you, I swear. I'm telling ya, give me all the stuff back!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_robbery_4_1">
        <text>Alright, if it's yours - then it's yours, none of my business, I was just sent here to take it. Take everything that's in the stash.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_robbery_4_2">
        <text>Maybe we can strike a deal? Let's make it 3k and we're square?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_robbery_4_3">
        <text>Listen you dickhead, I'll break your fucking skull myself!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_robbery_5_1">
        <text>There we go, did you really need to bitch about it? Now get out of here out of my sight, and never touch our stashes again, understood?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_robbery_5_2">
        <text>Are you really gonna pay for them? That thing is ours, we'll get three times more for it than you're offering! You sucker, give me the rock quickly or I'll break your head!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_robbery_6_1">
        <text>Alright, alright.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_robbery_6_2_1">
        <text>Don't need your fucking rock, take it and that's the end of it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_robbery_6_2_2">
        <text>Listen, if not this way or another - go to Bear and ask him about the stuff, I'm just an errand boy.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_exit_1">
        <text>Alright, yopta, you ready?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_exit_2_1">
        <text>One sec, I'll finish one business and be right back.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_exit_2_2">
        <text>Well, yeah, kinda like that.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_exit_3">
        <text>Ok, listen carefuly now, this is a very important info. This is a one way path, I'll guide you to the tunnel and after that you're on your own. Out of the tunnel you'll get to Darkscape, location has absolutely nothing of interesst, just the base of free stalkers, but obviously they won't be happy to see ya. So here you move through bushes until the bridge, stay close to me. We'll cross the bridge and that's almost it, you can almost see the tunnel. When you get out on the other side of the tunnel, you can go either West or North. If you choose North, you'll get into Dark Valley - there's our highest boss, in an old plant in the utmost North. West - there are tons of suckers, on that Cordon. We control an old factory there behind the old railroad tracks. \n
		That's kinda it, now we go fast and without extra noise.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandits_exit_4">
        <text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_exit_1">
        <text>Good evening. Ready for a hike?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_exit_2_1">
        <text>Not yet, I have to finish preparation.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_exit_2_2">
        <text>Sure.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_exit_3">
        <text>We've got a great idea: there is a shortcut here to the very edge of Swamps. Here, take the key from the gate... It is located to the West of this house. Follow that road behind the gate and you will get to abandoned building, there's also a car nearby. Get into the abandoned building and get outside from the other end, and the only thing left is to jump over the barbed wire. You will end up at a church, I'm sure you'll meet our guys there. Go to the West of them and you will find our base. Good luck!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_csky_exit_4">
        <text>Thanks! I'll be going now.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_found_stash_1">
        <text>Wassup bro. You found the stash?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_found_stash_2_1">
        <text>I'd be damned, they are sitting there quietly like lice. I'm still working on it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_found_stash_2_2">
        <text>There's only some kind of crap, papers, old maps... Why the heck would they need this? I guess these are only good for wiping up, he-he.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="dt2_bandit_found_stash_3">
        <text>Let's see... Yeah, total crap. Alright, you can take it, I don't need any of this shit.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>