<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_10">
		<text>I know one small anomaly, it can also absorb, but nobody likes it, I think you're wrong, there are no anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_11">
		<text>You're wrong, young man. Look at this fire. See the flickering? The fact is that it is at this point, right under our noses we see a phenomenon that does not threaten man! On the contrary, it is very responsive to our actions. We called him "White Flame". Do you feel warm? Here, it is impossible to light a fire on this place! No matter how hard we tried, we poured different combustible mixtures and even tried to set fire to it with a flamethrower. But everything just goes out when the fire gets into the field. But in contrast, it warms up if it is nearby, but does not burn, no matter how close you bring your hand, the sensors detect a steady temperature. But that's not all...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_12">
		<text>Oh, how... What else is wrong with it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_13">
		<text>He can cook food on it! Frying, cooking, even stewing, I try to understand how it regulates the temperature of the dishes in which the food is cooked, Spirit, our chef, says that he just talks to him, says: "Fry! And it warms up the frying pan, I saw for myself how he asked me to turn down the fire and the temperature dropped! Young man... Do you have any idea what this means for a man? If only we could understand how it works, gas, coal, even nuclear power plants... Everything would have changed! The future is coming to an end right under our noses! And we can have our hands on it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_14">
		<text> Unbelievable... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_15">
		<text>And you can help me... Not for free of course. Interested? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_16">
		<text> Of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_2">
		<text>What the hell... And what if... Sorry... Have we already started talking to you? I'm sorry, I... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_3">
		<text> No, no, it's not that simple.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_4">
		<text>And what if...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_5">
		<text>Yeah, it's like...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_6">
		<text>It's warm... Soothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_7">
		<text>That's terrible how... Scary to live.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_8">
		<text>Are you all right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blue_men_start_dialog_9">
		<text> Yeah, yeah. It's okay, I was swallowed up by this little anomaly. This is very interesting!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="NewTest_Dialog_1">
		<text>No you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ah_kovalev_start_dialog_1111">
		<text> So... So X is multiplied by sinus... And we divide 180 by X, when we have X... Um, yes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ah_kovalev_start_dialog_2222">
		<text>Hell, there's no way she can be here. It's not exactly from here, but how...?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ah_kovalev_start_dialog_3333">
		<text>If the calculations are correct... And they are loyal to Kovalev... True, yes, it seems impossible... À? What is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ah_kovalev_start_dialog_4444">
		<text>So, the radius is 3 meters, the diameter... 6.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ah_kovalev_start_dialog_5555">
		<text>Yes... It should be written down, all this should be written down. Every comma is important. Every digit, I almost understood...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ah_kovalev_start_dialog_6666">
		<text>No, no, no, no... Can't it be that simple, or can it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cancel_ah_0">
		<text>I'm here about the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cancel_ah_1">
		<text>How are the searches going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cancel_ah_2">
		<text>I'm still doing the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cancel_ah_3">
		<text>I couldn't find the samples you needed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cancel_ah_4">
		<text>That's too bad. This is a serious setback that will have a major impact on our research.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_1_quest_0">
		<text>I'm here to help you with your research.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_1_quest_1">
		<text>I hope you're not pretending to be my candidate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_1_quest_2">
		<text>I'm only interested in money so far.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_1_quest_5">
		<text>There's a lot of interesting anomalies that armed groups bypass here in military warehouses. I need samples from them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_1_quest_end_0">
		<text>I collected artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_1_quest_end_1">
		<text>Excellent.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_3_quest_0">
		<text>How do you know where the artifacts you need are?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_3_quest_1">
		<text>Our research team is part of the Scientific Research Institute of ChAZ. We are studying the area to find a way to destroy it or at least control it. We have learned a lot from the information received from the Gunslinger, including a map of the location of anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_3_quest_2">
		<text>So this is who marked the anomalies on the map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_3_quest_3">
		<text>The Red Forest has several anomalies of interest to us, the exact coordinates of the Gunners dropped along with the PDA in the tunnels. Find first the PDA and then the artifacts we are interested in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_3_quest_end_0">
		<text>I found the anomalies listed in PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_3_quest_end_1">
		<text>Here is your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_4_quest_0">
		<text>Are there any more artifacts you need?</text>
 	</string>
	<string id="chernov_4_quest_1">
		<text> Work on the creation of artificial artifacts was carried out even before the disaster. My supervisor used to live and work in Limansk. We stayed at his house for a long time, discussing scientific work. And if memory serves me right, then I saw something resembling an artifact even then. </text>
 	</string>
	<string id="chernov_4_quest_2">
		<text> What happened to your friend? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_4_quest_3">
		<text>I don't know, the evacuation from Limansk never happened. It is not known where its inhabitants went. But I remember the address of his house. Maybe we should check if the artifact is still there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_4_quest_end_0">
		<text>Limansk is in a terrible state. There are no residents there, but I managed to find the artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_4_quest_end_1">
		<text>It can't be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_5_quest_0">
		<text>What have we come to?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_5_quest_1">
		<text>Curious sample. Undeniable proof that artifacts can be obtained artificially.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_5_quest_2">
		<text>How is it possible that artifacts could have appeared before the zone appeared?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_5_quest_3">
		<text>Have you heard anything about artifact farms? Research has been going on in this direction for a long time. Doing this lab X-19, now destroyed. And "beds" for her served as a dead forest. The territory is dangerous. But we need any information. I think we should look for the rest of the technical documentation at the entrance to the laboratory. Maybe there are artifacts left on the bed. It is also worth checking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_5_quest_end_0">
		<text>Just like you said. Documentation and artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_5_quest_end_1">
		<text>Oh, that's great. Don't ask me how I knew it would all be there. Here is your reward. I hope for your silence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_6_quest_0">
		<text>Anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_6_quest_3">
		<text>A large group of mercenaries controls the Dead City area. Anomalous activity there is relatively weak, but we need artifacts from there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_6_quest_end_0">
		<text>Nice town and residents are hospitable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chernov_6_quest_end_1">
		<text>I'm glad you liked it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="juk_1_quest_0">
		<text>I'm ready to go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="juk_1_quest_3">
		<text>I'll note the anomalies I'm interested in. Can you get the artifacts out of there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="juk_1_quest_end_0">
		<text>I've completed your mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="juk_1_quest_end_1">
		<text>Here's the reward, just like I promised.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="juk_2_quest_0">
		<text>What else is there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="juk_2_quest_3">
		<text>New data is coming in. We don't all know about the zone. A lot of anomalies are still not on the map. I will note the approximate coordinates of their dislocations. But be careful, I'm sure they are not in the general database for a reason.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="juk_2_quest_end_0">
		<text>Here are the samples.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="juk_2_quest_end_1">
		<text>Okay, great.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="juk_3_quest_0">
		<text>As there any more tasks?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="juk_3_quest_3">
		<text>I want to send you to the most dangerous part of the area right now, Pripyat. I noted the anomalies I am interested in on the map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="juk_3_quest_end_0">
		<text>Task accomplished.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="juk_3_quest_end_1">
		<text>I hope it was worth it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_0">
		<text>So...?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_1">
		<text>Show the detector, I need to make sure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_10">
		<text>That you deserve.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_11">
		<text>No, it's a murky job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_12">
		<text>But...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_13">
		<text>It is. I have "Bear"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_14">
		<text>It is. I have "Elite"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_15">
		<text>It is. I have "Svarog"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_16">
		<text>Oh, I have a great "response"!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_17">
		<text>Here, I have a great Bear!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_18">
		<text> Eh... Man, you've been punched... It's not a detector.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_19">
		<text>What?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_2">
		<text>It is. I have a "Response"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_20">
		<text>Detector got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_21">
		<text> Well, as you know. My business is to suggest...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_22">
		<text>....and mine to refuse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_23">
		<text>Fourty on the tail has brought news. Are we going to sharpen the lanyards or are you going to do the job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_24">
		<text>Reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_3">
		<text>I don't have it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_4">
		<text>Are you a junkie? Get out of here, don't interfere with the work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_5">
		<text>Yeah, that'll do. Okay, look, here you go, here you go, and... Here is another one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_6">
		<text>Roger that, I'm on my way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_7">
		<text>And how can you be so sure there'll be something there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_8">
		<text>The Tarot's maps were wrong. Are you taking it or not?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_9">
		<text>Not so fast, what do I get for the job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_0">
		<text>So that's what I found in there, what is it, anyway? Some strange artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_1">
		<text>Hmm... Yes, this is what it should be. The devices were not wrong, yes... Yes!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_10">
		<text>Nothing complicated, you can handle it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_11">
		<text>You have no idea what's going on around here because of your ignorance! We are on the threshold of unimaginable discoveries! Of course, there are mistakes, but what you have brought is solid evidence! Damn it! Then it turns out... Yes, yes! We need to clarify something else! In the meantime... So, your reward... What currency are you in? Or I can give you a container with two sections for artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_12">
		<text>Hryvnias.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_13">
		<text>Rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_14">
		<text>Dollars.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_15">
		<text>Container.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_16">
		<text>Here you go. So... Now I need to...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_17">
		<text>You're a pleasure to deal with, you know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_2">
		<text>Wow, don't jump out of the combo, is that so important?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_3">
		<text>Wait, Stalker! You're looking at this kind of work, do you want to earn more?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_4">
		<text>Yes, what do you want this time?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_5">
		<text>No, I've had enough of this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_6">
		<text>Stop stalker! Don't be in a hurry to refuse! ...Okay! I will pay twice as much as I did last year. Well? Okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_7">
		<text>Double the amount? Okay, I'm interested in you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_8">
		<text>No, I'm done. Find another suicide bomber.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_1_quest_end_9">
		<text>Damn it! Whatever you want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_0">
		<text>...So?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_1">
		<text>Obviously, I'm not the only one doing research here. At the Research Institute of Agricultural Industry, my colleague Dubrov is doing similar research. The fact is that he hasn't been in touch for nineteen hours. I suppose the worst is that he is dead. But it's too unusual if they were attacked, even if they were mutants, or idiots looking for easy profit in the face of scientists, then his group, if they hadn't coped with it, would have contacted the military, they were very close there, and the bearing would have been disturbing, and here, the silence, as through the ground fell. Your task will be to get to the last coordinates from where he was contacted, find any leads, and even dead bodies. If you find dead bodies... Dubrov should have a laptop with all the notes about the work done, see if he has completed the task "3.7" If not, then do it. This is an examination of certain anomalies for inactive artifacts, you've already done it, whatever you find, bring it to me. But I hope it's any other byte, but don't... Enough dead bodies for us. So, already... That's it, that's it! Is the task clear? Look, it's very important, I need to know what happened to them, but I can't quit everything and go and find out what's going on, especially when you've proved that I'm very close to a solution.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_10">
		<text>Well?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_11">
		<text>Kovalev, I don't want to die. Even in the name of "fundamental" discoveries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_12">
		<text>But... Damn it! At least you know where to find me and what to do. I hope you'll listen to the voice of reason.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_13">
		<text>Behave.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_2">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_3">
		<text>What about Amber? He is very close. Contact them, let them do some reconnaissance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_4">
		<text>On "Amber-3" and without me there is enough trouble, we already have work on each employee for three.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_5">
		<text>What do I owe for that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_6">
		<text>No offense. Don't worry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_7">
		<text>No, I won't take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_8">
		<text>But why? After all, I have explained to you the importance of this! You are not the one who is chasing the flesh! We are on the verge of fundamental discoveries, a little more and we can... The applications of our research are limitless!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_9">
		<text>Yeah, fuck me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_0">
		<text> I'm a Kovalev...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_1">
		<text>Well? Are they alive? Is he alive? Did this jerk fuck up his laptop? Is the radio broken? Did all three have a broken walkie-talkie? Are they okay? After all, he always makes copies, the information must be at least partially saved! After all, he always said to me, "Make copies! You never know what will happen!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_10">
		<text>Yeah, I remember a double award. In any case, you deserve it. So in what currency?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_11">
		<text>Hryvnias.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_12">
		<text>Rublish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_13">
		<text>Dollars.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_14">
		<text> So what? Where are you going now? It's convenient to do business with you. Will you do something else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_15">
		<text>First, you answer me a few questions. And I'll think about whether I need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_16">
		<text>Come on. I will try to answer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_17">
		<text>What kind of research are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_18">
		<text>I am part of the Jupiter 6 scientists now based in the Amber 3 bunker, but this is temporary, after the Baffle Station has been turned on and the path to Jupiter is cut off, the entire Jupiter 6 bunker is considered missing and presumably dead, but I don't believe it all. Our research is focused on... How can I put this? Here. We study spatial holes, pocket measurements, parallel worlds, alternative realities...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_19">
		<text>Why do you think Jupiter 6 is working?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_2">
		<text> Calm down, I don't know where they are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_20">
		<text> Stop listing, I get it. È? Have you achieved any results?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_21">
		<text> Yes, of course. Look around you, there's a tutu house. It shouldn't be here, and what else is characteristic... It is completely empty. According to satellite photos, and to the questions of my father, who conducted the service here, there was no house before the evacuation. There is an old man at the pumping station, by the way, who is called Mikhalych, who claims that this house did not appear more than a couple of months ago. The patrols of the Clear Sky group confirm his words. There is a passageway here somewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_22">
		<text>Passage?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_23">
		<text>Yes, and it's the biggest in the area, others, you've studied them, much less, there you've found these "artifacts". If I find him... Who knows how things will turn out. Where do these holes lead to? Many have disappeared, we hear their scraps of requests for help, their cries of despair, who cries, who shoots themselves starving or thirsty, one thing's for sure, they can't find a way out of this anomaly, it's almost impossible to get out of it, but there have been isolated cases, people have gotten out of these units, nobody in their right mind, what they're telling us is delusional. Their testimony differs diametrically. One of them had a fog around him, he was shaving through the sandy desert, occasionally encountering a rusty skeleton of the same car that we never understood about the car, but interestingly, every time we came across it, in a rusty place, but with the trunk closed, he'd find the same old jar of canned food, and Dr. Pepper's tin can, as we understand it, had been shaving in the desert for months, sometimes meeting that car again and every time it was like he hadn't met it. I think if it weren't for his bang, he'd have died of thirst or hunger. His name was... God willing, God willing... Yarovenko Alexey. Exactly. Stalker is a loner. He ran away from the bloodsucker on the agro-industrial site and doesn't remember how he ended up in the desert.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_24">
		<text>What are these artifacts? Why are they "inactive"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_25">
		<text>And how did he get out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_26">
		<text>Says that he was taken under control by an entity similar to a humanoid shadow, and had no choice but to move his frozen legs behind it, so he was met by a mercenary patrol in Limanskoye. He stood and looked into the wall, but only poked him with a gun, like a house of cards. Now it's on the big ground, in the lab.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_27">
		<text>Don't you think Dubrov found a way in? I wonder how he will get out of it now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_28">
		<text>Because "Jupiter 6" was packed as a bunker of long maintenance, there will be enough supplies for years of crawling life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_29">
		<text>You see, they're deactivated away from their birth zone. The first artifacts we took out of the zone, but in laboratories they seemed to be preserved, and when they came back they blossomed. These artifacts you found were not from here. They weren't born here. Somehow they came into our dimension, and they were naturally preserved. We're trying to make a map of the holes in space using them, and what we see isn't good news.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_3">
		<text>That's it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_30">
		<text>That's it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_31">
		<text>With every year, the holes are getting bigger and bigger. Artifacts are not the only thing that comes to us from outside. Did you pay attention to the population of mutants? On their kinds? Such mutations in our conditions are impossible. Anyway not all. Here to take at least... Controller.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_32">
		<text>Yeah, I thought about it, I hope we're both wrong.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_33">
		<text>That's it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_34">
		<text> So what? Have you made a decision? We have a decent payment, and it's a right thing to do. Agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_35">
		<text> Okay. I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_36">
		<text>No, I'm done for now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_37">
		<text> You know where to find me when you change your mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_38">
		<text>Think about it? Have you changed your mind?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_39">
		<text>Yes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_4">
		<text>I came to the place you pointed out, searched everything around, but neither the bodies nor the Dubrov group itself were there, but I found his laptop. Task 3.7 wasn't finished, I bypassed all the remaining coordinates and collected samples.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_40">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_41">
		<text>Are you saying that the controllers came from another world?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_42">
		<text>It's just a theory so far. Nothing more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_43">
		<text> That's what happens? Have I investigated the locations of potential spatial holes? And could I get into one of them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_44">
		<text>Yeah, you did, did you? No, they are too small. Here, for example, in the vicinity of the church, the passage is quite large. So big that the whole house has passed through...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_46">
		<text>Fuck that... I'm out of here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_47">
		<text>Wait! Everything is in the buckle. From here we won't get anywhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_48">
		<text>Where's that confidence coming from?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_49">
		<text>Yes... You will not understand. Take it for granted.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_5">
		<text> Damn it... Damn... Give it all here, you've done your best. Well, if you haven't found the bodies, maybe they're still alive. Or maybe... Well, it's not your headache anymore. In what currency?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_6">
		<text>Hryvna.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_7">
		<text>Rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_8">
		<text>Dollars.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_2_quest_end_9">
		<text>You remember what we agreed on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_redirect_dialog_0">
		<text>What do we do next, Kovalev?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_redirect_dialog_1">
		<text>I'm sending you to my colleague, he wrote that he needs help, with all the rest of the work here, I can do it myself, you will only interfere. Okay, here's a mark for you, maybe we'll see each other again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_redirect_dialog_2">
		<text>I still need to perform a lot of calculations here. And you go to the north of the Chernobyl nuclear power plant. Skabinsky is already there. He has always been a suicidal person...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kovalev_redirect_dialog_3">
		<text>Our calculations are full of holes due to lack of information, but we have managed to find out where the anomaly that is out of the calculation is. Now it is being examined by our head Academician Skabinsky. He wanted to tell you something, I think you should hurry up, the place is dangerous. He shouldn't have gone there alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="markov_1_quest_0">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="markov_1_quest_2">
		<text>Why don't you ask your colleagues from Amber?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="markov_1_quest_3">
		<text> I work separately from the scientific group on Amber. These idlers haven't investigated the nearest anomalies so far. Find these artifacts and I will pay you well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="markov_1_quest_end_0">
		<text>With your samples.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="markov_1_quest_end_1">
		<text>Perfect work, young man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="markov_2_quest_0">
		<text>As there any more tasks?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="markov_2_quest_3">
		<text>In the neighboring area, which is called the Wild, strange fluctuations were found. It seems that there are formations of interest to us that are worth exploring.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="markov_2_quest_end_0">
		<text> I found them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="markov_2_quest_end_1">
		<text>Wonderful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="markov_3_quest_0">
		<text>Give me something more dangerous.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="markov_3_quest_3">
		<text> I didn't want to give you this assignment, but I can't wait. The research plan has to be done. There used to be a secret laboratory on the territory of Amber. Psi radiation here is incredibly high, which could not but affect the peculiarities of the local samples. It is necessary to prepare properly for this sortie.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="markov_3_quest_end_0">
		<text> It wasn't easy, but I got it all together.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="markov_3_quest_end_1">
		<text> Great, that's enough for me for a while.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_ah_0">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_ah_1">
		<text>Hello, Stalker, what are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_ah_10">
		<text>Then I have nothing to talk to you about, free.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_ah_11">
		<text>Wait, but maybe...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_ah_12">
		<text>Great, then let's get started.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_ah_2">
		<text>You don't care? I have things to do here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_ah_3">
		<text>None of your business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_ah_4">
		<text>Hmm... Business as usual. Do you want to earn money? Don't break, I know you're always broke.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_ah_5">
		<text>Let's say so, but at least explain the point.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_ah_7">
		<text>Very good. So, not far from here there are several anomalous zones, your task will be to get artifacts from there, I hope you have at least a detector?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_ah_8">
		<text>Yes, there is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_ah_9">
		<text>No more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_1_quest_0">
		<text>Problems?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_1_quest_1">
		<text>Yes, this area is full of mutants and bandits, and these idiots sent me here alone. How do they imagine I can do my job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_1_quest_2">
		<text>What's the task?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_1_quest_5">
		<text> There are some pretty hard anomalies here. Practically not found here. You need to get samples from them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_1_quest_end_0">
		<text>It wasn't easy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_1_quest_end_1">
		<text>But you did it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_2_quest_0">
		<text> Anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_2_quest_3">
		<text>Technical cemetery is a poorly researched territory, many people avoid it, although there are a number of curious anomalies. Find the artifacts there and bring them to me, I'll pay well for them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_2_quest_end_0">
		<text> Easy walk can't be called an easy walk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_2_quest_end_1">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_3_quest_0">
		<text>What's next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_3_quest_3">
		<text>As you see, without help, I'm like a handless man. I sent one stalker to the landfill to place prototypes in anomalies. But he disappeared somewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_3_quest_4">
		<text>In these places it's not surprising.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_3_quest_5">
		<text>My assistant placed two experimental specimens in the anomalies and then disappeared. Find his PDA, there must be the anomalies we need and then take the test samples.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_3_quest_end_0">
		<text>Your messenger was killed by bandits, but I was able to find your samples.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pirogov_3_quest_end_1">
		<text>And that's good.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sarik_dialog_0">
		<text>What's new?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sarik_dialog_1">
		<text>In the zone there is a new group of researchers, collecting artifacts throughout the zone. Well, as artifacts, garbage of all kinds, none of the stalkers would not even have taken on this, but they are looking for. Interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sarik_dialog_2">
		<text>How do I find them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sarik_dialog_3">
		<text>Not interested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sarik_dialog_4">
		<text>They're scattered all over the area. One, they say, was seen recently in the marshes. He was taking some measurements in a church.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_0">
		<text>How's it going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_1">
		<text>God, you found me. Are you ready to get into gigantic anomaly? Go deep into it, get into its dangerous center?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_2">
		<text> Could be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_3">
		<text>Please not.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_4">
		<text>It's extremely difficult to get there. Take this advanced detector, it shows the location of anomalies. So you will have a better chance of succeeding.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_5">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_6">
		<text>You hear that? The zone calls us. Move out. Go and take her gift. I'll be waiting for you here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_end_0">
		<text>I found an artifact on the generators.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_end_1">
		<text>Thank you, stalker. Science is in an invaluable debt to you. You deserve a worthy award. Let's get the artifact here soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_end_2">
		<text>Of course, take it, bro.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_end_3">
		<text>E, no. I'll need this artifact myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_end_4">
		<text>You're forgetting, we had a deal. We will not tolerate its violation!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_end_5">
		<text>Okay, okay, here's your artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_end_6">
		<text>With this artifact, I'm almost invulnerable. There is nothing you can do to me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_end_7">
		<text>Well, hold on, nits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_1_quest_end_8">
		<text>Thank you. Although our paths diverge here, we will always remember you. No money can appreciate your contribution to science, but this modest amount, I think, will not be superfluous. I advise you to immediately sit down for your thesis, your experience in studying anomalies is invaluable. Hopefully our paths will cross again, I will recommend you for admission to our institute. Thank you again. Have a good day with stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_fail_quest_0">
		<text>At last we met, how's the search going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_fail_quest_1">
		<text> Well, hello. Is that you, the stalker who helped our group with its research? Looks like we shouldn't have hoped for your help, the calculations are wrong, this damn place is not the center of the zone. Everything was in vain.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_fail_quest_2">
		<text>Can't you do anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skabinsky_fail_quest_3">
		<text>All you could do is you already did. Now get out. The failure of our operation is your fault.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_1">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_10">
		<text>I see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_11">
		<text>Ambitious plans.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_12">
		<text>Happy for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_13">
		<text>This never ends.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_14">
		<text>With us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_15">
		<text>In the Zone, you always have to think first and then do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_2">
		<text>Well, I know that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_3">
		<text>Very interesting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_4">
		<text>For a decent reward, of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_5">
		<text>Artifacts don't spread on bread.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_6">
		<text>What am I doing? I'm already upside down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_7">
		<text>I'm trying not to shine a light on the hubarom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_8">
		<text>Main, so it doesn't fall again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_answer_9">
		<text>I hope you haven't thought of throwing anomalies yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_1">
		<text>It's the coordinates of the anomalies. Examine them with the detector. There should be samples of interest to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_10">
		<text>We don't buy artifacts from stalkers or bandits. Without knowledge of the exact place of origin, they are useless to us. Our task is to collect samples from every corner of the zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_11">
		<text>Each artifact, even one kind of artifact - has a unique radiation depending on where it was found. On each of them, the zone has left a unique imprint that is not to be confused with anything else. Knowing the full spectrum of radiation, we can make a psionic map of the zone. Understand the origins of those disturbances that caused the zone. Or maybe we can control them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_12">
		<text>Thanks to you, our computing cluster is busy with calculations around the clock. Information for analysis for years to come. Still, it was the right decision, despite the risks, will be divided by the team throughout the territory. Here our head academician Skabinsky acted far-sightedly. It is impossible for one person to comprehend such a large structure in its entirety. It was only by combining our thinking skills that we could succeed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_13">
		<text>Thank you for being with us. Usually the stalkers that help us constantly disappear. Preliminary analysis of the spectrogram is full of surprises, it seems that the center of the zone has been under our nose all this time. Our colleague did not wait for the final calculations and has already moved there. But I am still inclined to finish drawing up the map. I'll get a few more samples.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_14">
		<text>Our case is coming to an end. Soon we will prove that we are worthy to take our place... You know that in the center of the zone there is a gigantic anomaly, and all the psy-lines intersect there? The artifact, which will be born in this unique place, will have unique properties. The zone will finally talk to us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_15">
		<text>Spot news. Our colleague has stopped contacting us. There is no reason to hope for the best, most likely he died. In the middle of the zone is a giga anomaly. It is almost impossible to pass it. We will think about how to solve this problem, maybe it is worth to clarify the calculations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_2">
		<text>As you may have already guessed, I'm working in the research group of the Institute for the Study of the Chernobyl Anomalous Zone. Artefacts are invisible to the human eye, but the frequency they emit can be registered by detectors.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_3">
		<text>Each artifact emits energy at its own frequency. It's like a fingerprint, the author's signature on a work of art. The wider the scanning range of the detector, the more artifacts it can find. As a rule, stalkers are looking for artifacts with outstanding properties. Meanwhile, any anomaly specimens are of interest to science.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_4">
		<text>As you know, the Arrower managed to figure out the secret of the Zone. This information is now available to many scientists. This has greatly advanced us in our understanding of the amazing nature of anomalies, how they affect the world around us and living organisms. Now we collect base of practical observations and measurements on district. This work is not easy to call simple. That's why we are looking for helpers from free stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_5">
		<text>The rupture of the noosphere, which everyone knows as the second explosion, was the reason for the creation of an abnormal zone. The power lines of the psi-fields, like a tentacle, envelop this area. Every object that is in the zone falls under their influence. Even you are already marked by the zone. What about the artifacts that are born in its womb. This is an amazing gift that not everyone can appreciate. And it's not about the money they're worth. Artifacts are messengers of the zone, through them she communicates with us. That's why we need them so much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_6">
		<text>Each artifact has a unique modulation, even if they are of the same type. It can tell us a lot about such a mysterious thing as noosphere. The stupidest thing you can do is cling them to your belts and hope that it will save you from bullets or anomalies. Now we're just getting to the bottom of it, and there are plans to make a full spectrogram of the zone, which will require a lot of territory to get around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_7">
		<text>Have you ever wondered what the artifacts are made of? Most often they are the remains of living beings caught in the anomaly. So the next time you decide to boast of a rare find, remember, it could be the remains of the same stalker. Well, or boar, who knows.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_8">
		<text>Anomalies are believed to be some kind of space-time ruptures where the physical laws of our world stop working. But there is another viewpoint that this is a powerful source of signal that we simply cannot accept. Who is transmitting them and why? Or maybe it's just the lid of a pot that rattles because of the boiling broth?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="story_line_dialog_9">
		<text>Anomaly most often chooses organic samples as the receiver of information. For example, wild animals or zombies that often die in them. This is how artifacts appear. Knowing the exact origin of an artifact, you can read it as a book or as a flash drive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="test_dialog_0">
		<text>There's anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="test_dialog_1">
		<text>Find an artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="test_dialog_2">
		<text>I'll find it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="test_dialog_3">
		<text> Don't </text>
	</string>
	<string id="test_dialog_4">
		<text>Okay</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vorobushkin_1_quest_0">
		<text>What's with the assignment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vorobushkin_1_quest_3">
		<text>Zaton is poorly researched. Calculations show that these places should contain the artifacts we are interested in. In order to pinpoint the anomalies to be investigated, I have restored the equipment at the "Circle" sounding station. It took time to scan, and it was dangerous to stay, so I'm here. To start our research, we had to get to the station and take the memory module. All the necessary data is there. By the way, there are some anomalies there, maybe they contain the right samples, but it will only be possible to say exactly after receiving the scanned data.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vorobushkin_1_quest_end_0">
		<text> Easy walk. Recovered data, found artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vorobushkin_1_quest_end_1">
		<text>Wonderful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vorobushkin_2_quest_0">
		<text>Other task?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vorobushkin_2_quest_3">
		<text>The following anomalies are well known but very dangerous. Be careful on the bridge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vorobushkin_2_quest_end_0">
		<text>Check.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vorobushkin_2_quest_end_1">
		<text>That's it.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
