<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="ls_header">
		<text>"STALKER DIARY"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_number">
		<text>Page ¹</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_1">
		<text>"An exhausted stalker is a dead stalker. A hungry stalker is a dead stalker. A sleepy stalker is a dead stalker. You do not want to be a dead stalker, do you?"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_2">
		<text>"Hunting for mutants is not only entertainment, but also a way to earn money selling pelts and body parts. Just remember, the one who shoots monsters, should make sure that in the process he himself does not become a monster."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_3">
		<text>"You are what you eat. However, by eating the controller's brain you will not get his abilities, unfortunately..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_4">
		<text>"Do not delude yourself, stalker. When in the Zone, the dog is no longer human's best friend."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_5">
		<text>"Batteries can be charged with dynamo. Someone told me that Sakharov has it for sale. Also some of the tech guys could have it."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_6">
		<text>"Note to self: weapons are brought to the Zone in different variants and packages. Each one has its own benefits and drawbacks."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_7">
		<text>"Grenades can do wonders. Always keep one or two at hand in case the shit hits the fan. If those do not help, then nothing will."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_8">
		<text>"The upkeep of one weapon costs a lot, the upkeep of many can ruin you. Stick to your choice and do not be so indecisive."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_9">
		<text>"A partner can stab you in the back, a bandit-partner will definitely do it, but a good rifle never betrays. Take care of it and it will take care of you."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_10">
		<text>"Local stalkers have their own measure of experience - rank, almost like in the army. Rank has eight different levels, starting with "Beginner" and ending with "Legend", although I have never seen anyone whose rank would be that high."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_11">
		<text>"Respect the established rules. Stalkers in camps won't speak to you when you brandish your weapon in their faces."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_12">
		<text>"Tools are required for most mechanics to perform repairs and improve weapons and armor. Such tools can often be found in stashes received as a reward for completing assignments, as well as on corpses."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_13">
		<text>"As one sage said: there are paths best not taken and places best not visited. Assess your chances before the start of the shootout."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_14">
		<text>"The boar has a very strong bony and muscular front. Shoot to the scruff or to the pelvis - those are most vulnerable parts. You can jump or hide behind obstacles to flank them while they rush towards you in rage."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_15">
		<text>"Feeling a rush of rage? Shoot hands and feet. Save the enemy's head and you might hear something interesting."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_16">
		<text>"If you are not able to find a decent bed to rest in the Zone, sleeping bags or tents are an excellent alternative. They can be purchased from most major traders or found in the stashes of other stalkers."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_17">
		<text>"Military helicopters patrol many places in the Zone. If the military participates in hostilities, they can request air support to destroy attacking or defending opponents."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_18">
		<text>"Groups in the Zone don't spend their time just sitting on their asses. Just because you have already cleared one place, it does not mean that it's safe and no one else will ever appear there. Some people claim they have seen Monolith soldiers in Cordon."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_19">
		<text>"Take higher ground and use natural shelters in battle. Even a stone can protect you from a pack of dogs. No, do not throw it at them, climb it, you moron!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_20">
		<text>"Backpacks are useful. They allow for additional portable weight and storage space and can be used to create personal caches, as well as other containers. You can also get rid of the backpack quickly with a quick release button and run away from danger more quickly without any extra weight on your shoulders."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_21">
		<text>"Relax by the campfire and have a taste of grilled boar chops. The food of the Zone is difficult to eat, but even harder to find. Take care of it and use it wisely."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_22">
		<text>"Yes, as it turns out, you really can see the Emission with your own eyes. But only once..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_23">
		<text>"Keep your ears tuned on the environment. Shooting in the distance indicates a shootout and, consequently, potential prizes."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_24">
		<text>"So many books to read, so many words and so little useful information. Because only life itself gives valuable knowledge, doesn't it?"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_25">
		<text>"We should prohibit the sale of imported goods. There is no one here who can test their quality. Eat only food produced in the Zone - be a real stalker."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_26">
		<text>"You better not touch the stuff of other stalkers in camps, especially when they are looking at you. If something is lying somewhere, most likely it belongs to someone. By the way, you can get a hit in the face or a bullet in the head for stealing."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_27">
		<text>"Performing tasks for groups will improve your relationships. Their merchants will gradually offer you bigger discounts on their goods and services. Eventually you will be able to recruit other stalkers to join your squad."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_28">
		<text>"Do not forget to ask simple stalkers if they have any assignments. The fact that they are not some important characters does not mean that they are not ready to pay for the work."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_29">
		<text>"Fasten a quarrel upon "Duty" and "Freedom" will like you, fasten a quarrel upon "Freedom" and "Duty" will like you. If you like conflicts, fight both of them."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_30">
		<text>"The Arena in Rostok conducts two types of competitions: traditional fights, where stalkers fight with each other for a cash reward, or fights where they try to kill increasingly more powerful mutants."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_31">
		<text>"A line from the notes of the guide: The night is fraught with beasts. If you need to leave shelter after dark - make sure that the stars or moon are there to guide you."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_32">
		<text>"Collect each cartridge in your path regardless of the caliber and hide it somewhere. Tomorrow you may need them ... or maybe not. But it's worth it anyway - cartridges are also a good source of income."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_33">
		<text>"Ammunition is known for its ability to run out, so even the greatest sniper might have to run for his life."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_34">
		<text>"You will never hit your target if you are afraid."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_35">
		<text>"Trust your ears. Sounds carries over hills, and through bushes. A weak, distant sound is enough to prepare for a sudden attack."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_36">
		<text>"Do not neglect your handgun. Keep it at hand as a backup weapon, with some extra ammo of appropriate type. You never know when you might need it."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_37">
		<text>"If you survive the Zone but lose your soul - you are no better than a mutant that feeds on carrion."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_38">
		<text>"Do not take your eyes off the sky. Birds and clouds are only some of the representatives of hell, you see them constantly. But if you see flashes and hear mutants howl and rumble - do not think, just run."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_39">
		<text>"When you fight - cheat, this is the only rule to win. Being fair is not as important as being alive."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_40">
		<text>"When you engage in a gunfight, keep calm, do not swear, wait for your turn and attack when the enemy reloads. Use grenades if the enemy takes cover."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_41">
		<text>"Better safe than sorry. Your only obligation is to survive."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_42">
		<text>"Remember: without splints and other ways to remedy the consequences of bone fractures, you inevitably will have to suffer incredible pain and hardly ever will make it to the nearest camp."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_43">
		<text>"It is always best to wait heavy rain through when you are sheltered, especially if your backpack is not water-proof."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_44">
		<text>"Did i ever tell you the definition of insanity? Insanity is hunting for the artefacts without proper equipment, that's what insanity is."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_45">
		<text>"Forewarned is forearmed. Collect as much information as possible before proceeding."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_46">
		<text>"If you are attacked by a controller, try to hide from his direct gaze, hide behind something (wood, stone, wall), perhaps this will save your mind. When he does not see you, he can not harm you."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_47">
		<text>"The best means of protection against mutants - the local Duty patrol"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_48">
		<text>"Stimpacks are quite useful. They heal wounds much quicker than medkits or other medicines."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_49">
		<text>"The helmet on your head, body armour and backpack greatly affects your mobility, you should always remember that."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_50">
		<text>"Always do the job in time and thoroughly, reputational loss will make you think of it sooner or later."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_51">
		<text>"Rookies in the Zone often make mistakes while dressing mutants and this is fine. Experience comes gradually with time and practice and skills are going to be improved."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_52">
		<text>"Never trust bandits. Even if they seem very friendly, know - they only want money and they will not think twice to stab you in the back."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_53">
		<text>"The military is not here to protect us from the Zone, so if you see a soldier, run for your life. Do not even dare to think of how it will appear to onlookers."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_54">
		<text>"Keep your equipment in good condition and it will keep you in good shape."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_55">
		<text>"Every madman who dares to lay a hand on the Zone can be certain that the Zone will gnaw it off."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_56">
		<text>"It is not worth it helping wounded enemies. The best gratitude you can expect from them is a bullet to your head when you lower your weapon."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_57">
		<text>"Moving at night or in heavy rain, it is easier to avoid being detected by enemies, but the higher the risk of encountering fierce night mutants. As well as the chance of your 12ga ammo becoming damp."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_58">
		<text>"Be a good leader! Don't abandon your partners, you will lose respect. Squadmates in a firefight or on patrol will not be able to travel with you."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_59">
		<text>"When repairing heavily damaged weapons, technicians will ask for huge sums of money. Spare parts do not appear from nowhere - they have to be paid for. So in fact it is often not worth it."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_60">
		<text>"Listen to the sounds of anomalies: your hearing can better determine its location, rather than your sight."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_61">
		<text>"Make sure that your weapons are always loaded. Only anarchists leave their magazines half empty."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_62">
		<text>"Prepare for the unexpected emission, always have medicine with you in case there are no shelters nearby. They will not be able to protect you completely, but, perhaps, they will allow you to reach a hiding place, before your brain gets fried."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_63">
		<text>"Consider stocking up on cartridges for your favorite gun before you have it. Even if you know you won't be bying it any time soon. Who knows, you may stumble upon it at any time. Although it will be a shame if you never find one."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_64">
		<text>"Take as little equipment as possible so that you can bring back more loot and sell it to merchants when you return. Apologies, "if" you return."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_65">
		<text>"Use your artifact detector as often as possible. Keep in mind that artifacts can appear even after the psi storm. Although some artifacts are even visible to human eye."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_66">
		<text>"Carefully inspect the areas you plan to pass through. You will save your life by noticing the bloodsucker before he sees you. If you were lucky enough to hear him - stop, turn to the sound and meet him with a smile. Ha, I'm just kidding."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_67">
		<text>"Never cross an enemy territory when the sun blinds you or unmasks you with light in the back. And it's even better not to cross enemy territory at all ".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_68">
		<text>"To Hell with morality. The Zone offers its own set of rules that have nothing to do with what you observed on the Great Earth."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_69">
		<text>"It is always better to have an armour in more or less good condition, than the one torn in parts, the latter won't be able to absorb a hit of enraged boar and you can get some pretty bad fractures."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_70">
		<text>"Yes, exoskeletons are quite useful - you can carry a lot of weight and enjoy bullet protection at the same time. But there is a catch - you will have to always carry spare batteries for the suit and you will be charging them constantly."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_71">
		<text>"Remember the sounds produced by mutants. Knowing the one who rushes at you will allow you to get out of the situation by the most effective ways."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_72">
		<text>"Always carry magazines with AP ammo for all of your guns. Mutants can't have bullet-proof vests, but hostile stalkers can."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_73">
		<text>"Not feeling well but everything seems to be normal? Just buy a dosimeter and some antirads, you are just having early signs of radiation sickness."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_74">
		<text>"God damn those springboards, this pain is unbearable, almost sure it's fractured. If only I had at least some vodka, it would help immediately..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_75">
		<text>"When you sneak up on someone or something - do not forget to turn off the flashlight!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_76">
		<text>"Be healthy. Do not use drugs, whenever possible eat healthy, not contaminated food, drink purified water and get enough sleep."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_77">
		<text>"Watch your mental state, relax with your favorite thing, to relieve stress. Most stalkers prefer pornographic journals, but you can be more creative."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_78">
		<text>"Reputation gives an idea of how stalker relates to his faction. It improves or worsens depending on one's actions towards other stalkers. The higher is your reputation - the better. One of the most significant benefits of high reputation is that traders will offer you better options to order or buy."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_79">
		<text>"The zone is alive, believe me. She eats, breathes... and it craps. When she craps, you'd better take shelter somewhere, if you do not want to be flushed down into the sewer."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_80">
		<text>"Surrounding beauty strikes me the most. We simply do not have enough time to admire the terrain, because the Zone can destroy us at a time when we least expect it to."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_81">
		<text>"Don't be too picky when asking for a job - stalkers can treat you like an idiot and stop giving you jobs altogether."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_82">
		<text>"Never underestimate a hungry dog. Where is one dog, there are ten."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_83">
		<text>"Be careful when approaching another stalker. Sometimes their hearts are much darker than the Zone itself."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_84">
		<text>"Do not trust anyone, there are enough traitors. Friendship is magic, even in the Zone."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_85">
		<text>"Day 1: My hair started falling out. Day 2: My skin began to peel off. Day 3: I can't move. Greed ... I wanted to save on medicine. Now it's too late.."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_86">
		<text>"It's always better to order something from the trader in advance, even if you don't have enough money yet. By the time your order arrives you will have enough opportunities to earn and save up."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_87">
		<text>"Whenever you feel depressed - sit down, have some rest by the fire, listen to music and maybe have a drink with fellow stalkers."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_88">
		<text>"Develop a habit of looking into every corner and every hole. You never know where or what may be hidden."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_89">
		<text>"The whole world fell into Hell. Economic collapse on the Big Land, and the Zone... The Zone is a tumor on the body of the Earth, and its fiery tongues of flame will devour you."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_90">
		<text>"The devil spoke, and with his words the Zone revived. And he gave birth to his powerful henchmen who bear his word and who will lead the world to destruction."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_91">
		<text>"When you decide to lie down at night - always have a weapon within reach. Although it's better not to lie down at all if you are outside, a tent will not save you as well."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_92">
		<text>"The two heads of the chimera reflect her nature. It will run away from you only to kill mercilessly a few seconds later. It will attack you from behind jumping out of the darkness."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_93">
		<text>"Bloodsuckers are masters of stealth. It's better to see them before they see you."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_94">
		<text>"The higher your skills are, the more time it will take to improve them any further. Thinking of becoming a jack-of-all-trades? Dream on."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_95">
		<text>"Controllers can stop you by taking possession of your mind. But they can not stop the RPG shot fired at their mouth."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_96">
		<text>"Obviously the majority of stalkers cannot use non-cash payments, this option is only available to the traders, who also can exchange the currency. But remember, every trader has his own exchange rate."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_97">
		<text>"Recently I've seen an expendable stalker trying to open a crate with a knife, these zoomers! Just smash it with your bare hands or feet, the wood is completely dry."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_98">
		<text>"It's easier to kill you when you stop. So never. Stop. Moving."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_99">
		<text>"Be careful, stalker. Death is always somewhere near. If you see it - aim at the head."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ls_tip_100">
		<text>"This son of a gun!... Said he didn't have any more bandages in stock! And I don't even have any rags at hand, even a single one would help to patch up my leg... Oh crap it's so bad, pouring like water from a tap, must have gone through the artery... I can see the world going dark before my eyes..."</text>
	</string>
</string_table>